<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Data Preprocessing - Category - Mohammed Arebi</title>
        <link>https://arebimohammed.github.io/categories/data-preprocessing/</link>
        <description>Data Preprocessing - Category - Mohammed Arebi</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>arebi.mohamed59@gmail.com (Mohammed Arebi)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>arebi.mohamed59@gmail.com (Mohammed Arebi)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 20:29:01 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arebimohammed.github.io/categories/data-preprocessing/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Applying Over-Sampling Methods to Highly Imbalanced Data</title>
    <link>https://arebimohammed.github.io/applying-oversampling/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 20:29:01 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://arebimohammed.github.io/applying-oversampling/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/Upsampling%20Applications/oversampling.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>I mentioned various undersampling approaches for dealing with highly imbalanced data in the earlier post &ldquo;Applying Under-Sampling Methods to Highly Imbalanced Data&rdquo; In this article, I present oversampling strategies for dealing with the same problem.
By reproducing minority class examples, oversampling raises the weight of the minority class. Although it does not provide information, it introduces the issue of over-fitting, which causes the model to be overly specific. It is possible that while the accuracy for the training set is great, the performance for unseen datasets is poor.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Applying Under-Sampling Methods to Highly Imbalanced Data</title>
    <link>https://arebimohammed.github.io/applying-under-sampling/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 20:29:01 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://arebimohammed.github.io/applying-under-sampling/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/Undersampling%20Applications/undersample.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Class imbalance can lead to a significant bias toward the dominant class, lowering classification performance and increasing the frequency of false negatives. How can we solve the problem? The most popular strategies include data resampling, which involves either undersampling the majority of the class, oversampling the minority class, or a combination of the two. As a consequence, classification performance will improve. In this article, I will describe what unbalanced data is, why Receiver Operating Characteristic Curve (ROC) fails to measure accurately, and how to address the problem.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
